The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Fifty-First Episode
King Nylon
The fortress to the South has
been occupied by the enemy!
All the soldiers in the
fortress have been killed!
For the fortress to the
North there is no more hope!
The fortress to the West is destroyed!
Union X is now close.
I had ordered that our army...
...be divided into
four equal parts.
...and defend the borders from the
East, West, North, and South fortresses!
But there are no
troops in any fortress!
Where the hell has the
Silverland army gone?
Where has Duralumin gone
at this critical moment?
You are late,
Grand Duke Duralumin.
What happened
to the army of Silverland?
Answer me, Grand Duke Duralumin!
Have you gone mad, Prime Minister?!
- It's Union X!
- Duralumin, what does this mean?
I've taken out the dignitaries!
These you see are
the brave warriors of Union X.
From now on,
I will be the King of Silverland!
You all, instead, will die!
Grand Duke, you are a traitor!
It's the end for you!
Help! Stop him!
Kill those three nobodies!
- Sapphire, come here!
- Stop them!
This is the room of skeletons
Come!
Grand Duke Duralumin
has played a double game!
Let's kill the traitor!
All those who side
with the King... will die!
Have you lost your mind,
Grand Duke Duralumin?
We must defeat the Grand Duke
and help their Majesties!
Very well... Very well...
I obey...
Here is how those
who act against me will be treated!
No one else will be able to enter
this room,
unless they tear down the walls.
We can't leave anymore either?
No, Sapphire.
Only you can do it.
Listen: a long time ago,
there was a traitor.
The King and his family,
back then too, locked themselves away...
...in the room of skeletons
and the Prince...
...managed to get out of here
on his own.
He defeated the traitor
and liberated the country.
- What became of the King and the Queen?
- They died in here,
but the Prince rebuilt
this land beautifully.
So, Sapphire, you too..
I can't!
I can't let you die! No!
- My dear mom and dad...
- Poor Sapphire, my daughter..!
I will stay here with you.
Sapphire, you must respect
your father's will.
Don't forget
that you will succeed me on the throne.
This is an order and you must
respect the King's orders!
Now you must flee from here and punish
the traitor at any cost!
Look, Sapphire: this secret passage
is so narrow...
...that only a child
can pass through it.
You will leave through this passage
and take this with you.
Legend says that the golden ball
represents the Royal Family,
the silver one Silverland,
and the copper one the people!
These three spheres have the power
to defend our beloved kingdom.
Now move, my son,
you must go now!
Father...
Courage.
- Mother!
- Don't hesitate, Sapphire.
Go and fight, Sapphire, for
the salvation of the kingdom!
This is your destiny! Farewell,
Sapphire! Remember us.
- Sapphire!
- Dad! Mom!
I will return to save you,
so wait for me with faith!
Get moving! Knock
down that rock! Hurry up!
They all bear the mark of X.
We must finish the
coronation ceremony of Plastic...
...before X arrives. Gather
the men in the courtyard!
Yes!
Finally, now Silverland is mine!
I am a messenger
of the Union X army.
X and his army are
less than 5 kilometers from here.
Is everything ready to receive them?
5 kilometers from here?
Then there is no time
for the ceremony!
Listen to me, everyone! From this
moment, Plastic, my son,
is crowned King of Silverland!
And I, Duralumin,
will assume the regency.
Does anyone have any objections?
Ring the bell
to celebrate this event!
One moment! I'll ring it!
Because my son has become King!
Nylon! You traitor!
No! No! I have nothing to do with it! No! Help!
Enough! Enough! Enough!
I am the King now!
I have become the King of Silverland!
Page, clean my face at once!
Quick, you scoundrel! Quick!
And now I want to eat!
My back is stiff!
Stop it!
Who the hell are you?
Answer King Nylon!
King Nylon, it's over for you!
Ho... Ho... How dare you
to your King...?!
- Which King?
- I... am the King!
Where are you running?
X is coming
with his army!
What?! Finally!
- I was waiting for you, dear X!
- Stop!
Welcome, Excellency!
Welcome a thousand times!
I love you! You don't know how
happy I am to see you, my friend!
I couldn't wait for you to arrive!
Help me, please! Kill this
guy who is chasing me!
You finished him off!
Listen, X:
this land will never die!
As long as these three spheres exist,
You will not be able to destroy
the kingdom of Silverland!
Don't let him escape!
The mysterious knight?!
Dad, mom...
I'll come back with Franz to save you.
Wait for me, please!
Opale!
And Sapphire? And Sapphire?
Franz! Listen, Franz!
The King and Queen are in danger!
Franz, why are you turning away?
What did I say? What's happening to you?
How do you know what's happening
in the castle?
You went there because you are
in love with Sapphire, right?
Sapphire is closer to you than to me:
that's why you know so well
what happens in the castle!
Tell Sapphire that I don't want to
see her again! You take care of her!
In reality, I am nothing,
absolutely nothing to her!
I'm just a stupid stubborn fool!
Goodbye.
Please, you protect Sapphire.
- Opale, get out of the way!
- Franz!
But then it's you, Sapphire?!
And to think I had
never recognized you!
We must free them! We must
free your father and your mother!
They are no longer here.
They must have taken them...
...and they must have locked them up in
some other part of the castle.
Oh, no! They aren't even here!
Oh, my dear mother and father!
Where are you?
Take heart, Sapphire!
Stay calm, Sapphire.
We will find them somewhere.
X orders that anyone who finds
Princess Sapphire...
...must execute her immediately,
on pain of their own life! These
are the orders of the X Union!
How are we going to get around the castle? It'll be full of soldiers!
We have to try, Sapphire.
Remember what Union X commands you!
- Where should we look? - We'll scour every corner of this castle.
- Do you think we'll make it?
- Certainly.
The trouble is, we don't have much time.
Maybe it's best if we split up, that way we can search better. What do you say?
- All right.
- Now, listen to me:
you search on one side and I'll search on the other.
So we are agreed,
we'll meet back here in thirty minutes.
I'll go first.
Greetings, Your Excellency!
What do you think of my idea?
The news, by now, must have
reached every corner of the kingdom.
Even the most remote!
Sapphire must have
found out about it...
...and perhaps, by now, she is
already headed for the Northern pasture!
It's a trap, just as I suspected.
Baron Nylon,
you are speaking too loudly.
You called me "Baron"?!
Fool! I am the King,
don't you know?
No, you are still Baron Nylon.
X has decided this.
How strange... His Excellency X
had promised to make me King!
That's why I put on this crown!
Excellency, you promised
that whoever received you...
...would be King!
Isn't it true, Excellency?
I never keep promises!
What do you mean you
never keep promises?
Yes, exactly. Do you have
anything to say about that, Nylon?
Now I will go. You go
in the opposite direction.
You'll see that everything will be fine.
We will find your parents, Sapphire.
No! No! Away! Away! Go away!
Get out of here!
No! No! No! Leave me alone! Away!
Away! Away!
Away! Away! Forgive me, Duralumin!
Do not hold a grudge against me!
Please! I'll give this back to you!
Anything you want!
Nylon, I will not forget
your betrayal!
No! No! No, forgive me! No!
I'm waiting for the King and the Queen
in hell,
but they haven't arrived yet.
I have come to take them.
Tell me, where are they now?
The King and the Queen
are to be executed.
...on Skeleton Island,
in the Western Sea, tonight!
- Executed?!
- They were sent to the coast.
..with a private carriage,
a few hours ago!
Sapphire! Sapphire!
"I am Sapphire.
I'm going to the North pasture.
That's where my parents are"
Dad! Mom! I'm coming to free you!
- Didn't you know it was a trap?
- Damn it, Opal!
Opal, let's try to escape!
Quick, tell me the truth! Where
are the King and the Queen?
We took them to
Skeleton Island...
...and tonight they
will be executed.
Executed?!
God in heaven, please, protect
my mother and my father!
Mom! Dad! Mom!
The sun has already set.
Franz!
Where are my parents?
I discovered the boat
that was about to set sail...
...and I thought of getting
on to go and get them, but...
Mom! Dad!
Don't cry, Sapphire.
Now you have something to do!
Mother! Father!
Be strong, Sapphire. Now you have
a great task to fulfill:
that of fighting to free
your country from the oppressor!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP